<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>The Photonics Spotlight</title>
<description>Blog articles on topics in photonics, particularly laser technology and application.</description>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight.html?s=rss</link>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>RP Photonics Consulting GmbH, 2020</copyright>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 18:25:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Time to Start Digital Marketing with RP Photonics - with a Discount</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_07_08.html?s=rss</link>
<description>More photonics companies than ever have started digital marketing with RP Photonics in recent months. Currently, that can be done with a discount due to the coronavirus crisis, although the value of that advertising has by no means been diminished.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 8 Jul 2020 18:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_07_08.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Digital and Interactive Methods of Supporting the Photonics Industry</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_05_11.html?s=rss</link>
<description>RP Photonics supports many companies and research groups with various kinds of digital services. Additional interactive methods have been implemented to further increase the benefits.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 12:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_05_11.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Photonics Marketing in Times of the Coronavirus Crisis</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_04_01.html?s=rss</link>
<description>While the importance of marketing remains crucial in times of a crisis, we are deprived of some of the instruments and also need to be particularly careful to spend advertising money wisely. This article presents some thoughts which will hopefully support wise decisions.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 1 Apr 2020 10:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_04_01.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Laser Physics Helps to Understand the Corona Virus Crisis</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_03_16.html?s=rss</link>
<description>Because laser operation involves some similar aspects as the spread of an epidemic, in particular exponential growth and threshold behavior, one can in fact develop a clearer picture of what kind of measures has a real chance to avoid a catastrophic development of the current corona virus (SARS-CoV-2 / COVID-19) crisis. Clearly, stopping exponential growth of infections is absolutely vital, while other suggested solutions are bound to fail completely.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 17:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_03_16.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>News on the RP Photonics Website</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_01_20.html?s=rss</link>
<description>Heavy work has been performed in recent months on the RP Photonics website: many new encyclopedia articles, sponsoring, website tours, and security improvements.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 18:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2020_01_20.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Are Large Mode Areas Problematic?</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2019_11_19.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is explained why both large mode areas fibers and bulk laser resonators with large mode areas tend to be substantially less robust than others. The fundamental reason behind that is related to the reduced effect of diffraction. That also has implications for the power scaling of lasers.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 11:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2019_11_19.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can Monochromatic Light be Unpolarized?</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2019_08_26.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is explained what unpolarized light really is, and whether light can be unpolarized when it is (pseudo-)monochromatic.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 18:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2019_08_26.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Articles in the RP Photonics Encyclopedia</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2019_03_01.html?s=rss</link>
<description>In recent weeks, a substantial number of new articles has been added to the RP Photonics encyclopedia. This also further strengthens the value of the RP Photonics Buyers Guide for both readers and advertisers.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 1 Mar 2019 18:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2019_03_01.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Relevance of Photonics Buyer's Guides for Users and Advertisers</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_11_19.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is discussed in which ways buyers guides in the area of photonics are relevant for users (buyers) and for suppliers (advertisers). Also, practical criteria for selecting a suitable resource are given. Further, the article explains important fundamental aspects of branding and lead generation.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 12:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_11_19.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Resonator Modes in Microchip Lasers</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_09_28.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is explained how the resonator modes of a microchip laser are formed by thermal lensing effects. Some example cases are analyzed, showing that the concept works well for a 1-W laser, while beam quality will be lost for substantially higher power levels.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 17:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_09_28.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What is Different for Quasi-Three-Level Lasers?</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_08_22.html?s=rss</link>
<description>Compared with four-level gain media, quasi-three-level gain media behave differently in many respects. It is important to understand which statements on four-level lasers are also valid for three-level lasers, and which laser simulation software can be used for them.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_08_22.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on Thermal Lensing</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_07_16.html?s=rss</link>
<description>Thermal lensing is relevant in many solid-state bulk lasers and amplifiers. Here, a number of important questions on that topic are answered.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 18:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_07_16.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Intensity Noise</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_06_08.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is explained why the term  intensity noise is somewhat problematic in laser technology; what is actually meant, is noise of the optical power. Further, the importance of the considered range of noise frequencies is discussed. Depending on the used detector and the measurement time, you may get quite different results for the intensity noise.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 8 Jun 2018 18:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_06_08.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gain Saturation in Solid-state Lasers</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_05_11.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is explained how to apply the saturation intensity or saturation fluence for determining when gain saturation sets in. The example of spiking of a laser illustrates that well.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 18:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_05_11.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Laser Physics: the Essential Roles of Phonons in Solid-state Lasers</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_04_06.html?s=rss</link>
<description>The host medium of a laser crystal or glass does much more than just suspending the laser-active ions. In particular, phonons of the host medium often play crucial roles for laser operation.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 6 Apr 2018 09:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_04_06.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dependence on Raman Conversion on the Optical Bandwidth</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_03_05.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It has been found a couple of years ago that Raman conversion in a fiber gets substantially weaker if the bandwidth of the laser light is increased from below 1 nm to several nanometers. Here, the physical reason for that is explained and illustrated with some numerical simulations.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 5 Mar 2018 17:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_03_05.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Self-starting of Passively Mode-locked Lasers</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_01_08.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is important to obtain reliable self-starting of passively mode-locked lasers, and thus interesting to consider phenomena which influence that. Here, we discuss the surprisingly strong influences of parasitic reflections and the benefit of using a slow saturable absorber.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 8 Jan 2018 17:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2018_01_08.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Energy Levels of Solid-state Gain Media</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2017_12_04.html?s=rss</link>
<description>Energy levels of tibial solid-stayed laser gain media are grouped in level manifolds; the article discusses some important aspects of those. In practice, that aspect does usually not force us to make laser models substantially more complicated.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 4 Dec 2017 18:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2017_12_04.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gaussian Apertures in Resonator Models: Not Only for Exotic Lasers, But Also for Gain Guiding</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2017_11_02.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is shown that gain guiding effects can be taken into account in resonator design software when it supports Gaussian apertures. In some situations, the effects on the resonator modes are substantial.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 2 Nov 2017 15:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2017_11_02.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Importance of Spectral Wings on the Pulse Duration</title>
<link>https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2017_10_03.html?s=rss</link>
<description>It is well known that an optical bandpass filter can increase the duration of an ultrashort pulse. The article shows that that effect can be quite pronounced, even if the filter only attenuate the extreme spectral wings.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 3 Oct 2017 18:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rp-photonics.com/spotlight_2017_10_03.html</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
